¬ Generated by localisation spreadsheet
{guild_recruit_merchant_EXPIRY_LIMIT}It appears there are sufficient merchants for the time being. The Guild no longer requires you to recruit a merchant.
{guild_recruit_priest_EXPIRY_LIMIT}It appears there are enough of God's soldiers for the time being. The Guild no longer requires you to recruit a priest. 
{recruit_priest_EXPIRY_LIMIT}It appears there are enough of God's servants for the time being. The Guild no longer requires you to recruit a priest. 
{POPE_MISSION_SOURCE}The Pope
{COUNCIL_MISSION_SOURCE}Council of Nobles
{EXPLORERS_GUILD_MISSION_SOURCE}Explorers' Guild
{ASSASSINS_GUILD_MISSION_SOURCE}Assassins' Guild
{MERCHANTS_GUILD_MISSION_SOURCE}Merchants' Guild
{MASONS_GUILD_MISSION_SOURCE}Masons' Guild
{LARGE_PAPAL_STANDING_PENALTY_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope has suffered enormously.
{LARGE_PAPAL_STANDING_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope will suffer enormously. 
{MED_PAPAL_STANDING_PENALTY_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope has suffered significantly.
{MED_PAPAL_STANDING_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope will suffer significantly.
{SMALL_PAPAL_STANDING_PENALTY_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope is not as high as it once was.
{SMALL_PAPAL_STANDING_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope will not be as high as it once was.
{SMALL_PAPAL_STANDING_REWARD_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope has improved slightly.
{SMALL_PAPAL_STANDING_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope will improve slightly.
{MED_PAPAL_STANDING_REWARD_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope has improved.
{MED_PAPAL_STANDING_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope will improve. 
{LARGE_PAPAL_STANDING_REWARD_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope has improved significantly.
{LARGE_PAPAL_STANDING_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope will improve significantly.
{HUGE_PAPAL_STANDING_REWARD_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope has improved enormously.
{HUGE_PAPAL_STANDING_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}Your reputation with the Pope will improve enormously. 
{VNV_ADORED_BY_POPE_DESCR}The Pope considers your leader one of his closest allies.
{VNV_ADORED_BY_POPE_PRE_DESCR}Your leader will become one of the Pope's closest allies. 
{VNV_POPES_ENFORCER_DESCR}Your leader is the steel gauntlet of the Pope's will.
{VNV_POPES_ENFORCER_PRE_DESCR}Your leader will become the steel gauntlet of the Pope's will.
{PLACE_OF_WORSHIP_REWARD_DESCR}The Masons' Guild has built you a place of worship.
{PLACE_OF_WORSHIP_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}The Masons' Guild have offered to construct place of worship for you.
{MOD_MERCHANTS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_DESCR}The Merchants' Guild is thankful to you.
{MOD_MERCHANTS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}The Merchants' Guild will be thankful to you.
{MOD_MERCHANTS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_DESCR}The Merchants' Guild is impressed with you.
{MOD_MERCHANTS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}The Merchants' Guild will be impressed with you.
{MIN_MERCHANTS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_DESCR}The Merchants' Guild is appreciative of your efforts.
{MIN_MERCHANTS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}The Merchants' Guild will be appreciative of your efforts.
{MIN_MERCHANTS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_DESCR}The Merchants' Guild is now disappointed with you.
{MIN_MERCHANTS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}The Merchants' Guild will be disappointed with you.
{MAJOR_EXPLORERS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_DESCR}The Explorers' Guild is very happy with you.
{MAJOR_EXPLORERS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}The Explorers' Guild will be very happy with you
{MAJOR_EXPLORERS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_DESCR}The Explorers' Guild is very disappointed in you.
{MAJOR_EXPLORERS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}The Explorers' Guild will be very disappointed in you.
{MIN_ASSASSINS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_DESCR}The Assassins' Guild appreciates your efforts.
{MIN_ASSASSINS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}The Assassins' Guild is far from impressed with your efforts.
{MIN_ASSASSINS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}The Assassins' Guild will be not impressed with your efforts.
{FACTION_STANDING_REWARD_DESCR}You have genuinely improved your relations with this faction.
{FACTION_STANDING_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}You will improve your relations with this faction.
{FACTION_STANDING_PENALTY_DESCR}This faction thinks less of you.
{FACTION_STANDING_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}You will disappoint this faction.
{MIN_THIEFS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_DESCR}The Thieves' Guild is appreciative of your efforts.
{MIN_THIEFS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}The Thieves' Guild will be appreciative of your efforts.
{MIN_THIEFS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_DESCR}The Thieves' Guild is now disappointed with you.
{MIN_THIEFS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}The Thieves' Guild will be disappointed with you.
{MIN_THEOLOGIANS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_DESCR}The Theologians' Guild is appreciative of your efforts.
{MIN_THEOLOGIANS_GUILD_POINTS_REWARD_PRE_DESCR}The Theologians' Guild will be appreciative of your efforts.
{MIN_THEOLOGIANS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_DESCR}The Theologians' Guild is now disappointed with you.
{MIN_THEOLOGIANS_GUILD_POINTS_PENALTY_PRE_DESCR}The Theologians' Guild will be disappointed with you.
{blockade_heretic_TITLE}Blockade Port
{blockade_heretic_PROPOSAL}The Pope wishes you to blockade this port for at least 3 turns. Such chastisement will serve to both punish these heretics and stop their unholy rot from spreading to the faithful.
{blockade_heretic_EXPIRY_SETTLEMENT_TAKEN}This settlement has been taken, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_heretic_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated. You are no longer trusted to blockade this port.
{blockade_heretic_EXPIRY_RECOMMUNICATED}As this faction has returned to the fold and been reconciled, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_heretic_EXPIRY_BLOCKADED}This port is already blockaded, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_heretic_FAILURE}You have let down the Pope and the Almighty by unsuccessfully blockading this port.
{blockade_heretic_SUCCESS}You have pleased the Pope and the Lord by successfully blockading this port.
{blockade_pagan_TITLE}Blockade Port
{blockade_pagan_PROPOSAL}The Pope wishes you to blockade this port for at least 3 turns. Such chastisement will serve to both punish these heathens and stop their unholy rot from spreading to the faithful.
{blockade_pagan_EXPIRY_SETTLEMENT_TAKEN}This settlement has been taken, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_pagan_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated. You are no longer trusted to blockade this port.
{blockade_pagan_EXPIRY_RECOMMUNICATED}As this faction has come to the fold, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_pagan_EXPIRY_BLOCKADED}This port is already blockaded, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_pagan_FAILURE}You have let down the Pope and the Almighty by unsuccessfully blockading this port.
{blockade_pagan_SUCCESS}You have pleased the Pope and the Lord by successfully blockading this port.
{blockade_islam_TITLE}Blockade Port
{blockade_islam_PROPOSAL}The Pope wishes you to blockade this port for at least 3 turns. Such chastisement will serve to weaken these enemies of the Holy Mother Church.
{blockade_islam_EXPIRY_SETTLEMENT_TAKEN}This settlement has been taken, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_islam_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated. You are no longer trusted to blockade this port.
{blockade_islam_EXPIRY_RECOMMUNICATED}As this faction has come to the fold, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_islam_EXPIRY_BLOCKADED}This port is already blockaded, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{blockade_islam_FAILURE}You have let down the Pope and the Almighty by unsuccessfully blockading this port.
{blockade_islam_SUCCESS}You have pleased the Pope and the Lord by successfully blockading this port.
{city_small_church_TITLE}Build a Small Church
{city_small_church_PROPOSAL}It has come to His Holiness's attention that this city is bereft of a proper place of worship. The Pope wishes you to build a Small Church in this city.
{city_small_church_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this city, you are no longer charged with building a Small Church there.
{city_small_church_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated; the Pope cares naught what you build in this city.
{city_small_church_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to build a Small Church in this city, and thus hampering the proper worship of the Lord in this city.
{city_small_church_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully building a Small Church in this city, and thus propagating the proper worship of the Lord in this city.
{city_abbey_TITLE}Build an Abbey
{city_abbey_PROPOSAL}It has come to His Holiness's attention that this settlement is bereft of a proper place of worship. The Pope wishes you to build an Abbey in this settlement.
{city_abbey_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this city, you are no longer charged with building an Abbey there.
{city_abbey_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated; the Pope cares naught what you build in this city.
{city_abbey_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to build an Abbey in this city, and thus hampering the proper worship of the Lord in this city.
{city_abbey_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully building an Abbey in this city, and thus propagating the proper worship of the Lord in this city.
{city_cathedral_TITLE}Build a Cathedral
{city_cathedral_PROPOSAL}It has come to His Holiness's attention that this city is bereft of a proper place of worship. The Pope wishes you to build a Cathedral in this city.
{city_cathedral_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this city, you are no longer charged with building a Cathedral there.
{city_cathedral_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated; the Pope cares naught what you build in this city.
{city_cathedral_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to build a Cathedral in this city, and thus hampering the proper worship of the Lord in this city.
{city_cathedral_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully building a Cathedral in this city, and thus propagating the proper worship of the Lord in this city.
{city_huge_cathedral_TITLE}Build a Huge Cathedral
{city_huge_cathedral_PROPOSAL}It has come to His Holiness's attention that this city is bereft of a proper place of worship. The Pope wishes you to build a Huge Cathedral in this city.
{city_huge_cathedral_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this city, you are no longer charged with building a Huge Cathedral there.
{city_huge_cathedral_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated; the Pope cares naught what you build in this city.
{city_huge_cathedral_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to build a Huge Cathedral in this city, and thus hampering the proper worship of the Lord in this city.
{city_huge_cathedral_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully building a Huge Cathedral in this city, and thus propagating the proper worship of the Lord in this city.
{castle_small_chapel_TITLE}Build a Small Chapel
{castle_small_chapel_PROPOSAL}It has come to His Holiness's attention that this castle is bereft of a proper place of worship. The Pope wishes you to build a Small Chapel in this castle.
{castle_small_chapel_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this castle, you are no longer charged with building a Small Chapel there.
{castle_small_chapel_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated; the Pope cares naught what you build in this castle.
{castle_small_chapel_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to build a Small Chapel in this castle, and thus hampering the proper worship of the Lord in this castle.
{castle_small_chapel_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully building a Small Chapel in this castle, and thus propagating the proper worship of the Lord in this castle.
{castle_chapel_TITLE}Build a Chapel
{castle_chapel_PROPOSAL}It has come to His Holiness's attention that this castle is bereft of a proper place of worship. The Pope wishes you to build a Chapel in this castle.
{castle_chapel_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this castle, you are no longer charged with building a Chapel there.
{castle_chapel_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated; the Pope cares naught what you build in this castle.
{castle_chapel_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to build a Chapel in this castle, and thus hampering the proper worship of the Lord in this castle.
{castle_chapel_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully building a Chapel in this castle, and thus propagating the proper worship of the Lord in this castle.
{guild_recruit_spy_TITLE}Train Spy
{guild_recruit_spy_PROPOSAL}Sometimes a little bit of information is worth a dozen armies. The Guild requests that you train a Spy in this settlement.
{guild_recruit_spy_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this settlement, the Guild no longer expects you to train a Spy there.
{guild_recruit_spy_FAILURE}You have failed to train a Spy; the Guild is disappointed with this result.
{guild_recruit_spy_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully trained a Spy, the Guild is very pleased.
{guild_recruit_merchant_TITLE}Train Merchant
{guild_recruit_merchant_PROPOSAL}Three things are required to make war and conquest; gold, gold and more gold. The Guild requests that you train a Merchant in this settlement.
{guild_recruit_merchant_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this settlement, the Guild no longer expects you to train a Merchant there.
{guild_recruit_merchant_FAILURE}You have failed to train a Merchant; the Guild is disappointed with this result.
{guild_recruit_merchant_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully trained a Merchant, the Guild is very pleased.
{guild_recruit_priest_TITLE}Train Priest
{guild_recruit_priest_PROPOSAL}The Holy word requires another soldier of faith. The Guild requests that you train a Priest in this settlement.
{guild_recruit_priest_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this settlement, the Guild no longer expects you to train a Priest there.
{guild_recruit_priest_FAILURE}You have failed to train a Priest; the Guild is disappointed with this result.
{guild_recruit_priest_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully trained a Priest, the Guild is very pleased.
{blockade_moderate_TITLE}Blockade Port 
{blockade_moderate_PROPOSAL}It is time we apply pressure upon our foes. Sending a fleet to blockade this port for at least 2 turns will not only hurt our enemy, but it will fill our coffers.
{blockade_moderate_EXPIRY_SETTLEMENT_TAKEN}This port has been taken; you are no longer expected to blockade it.
{blockade_moderate_EXPIRY_ALLIED}This faction has become an ally; you are no longer required to blockade this port.
{blockade_moderate_EXPIRY_BLOCKADED}It appears this port is already blockaded; you are no longer required to blockade it.
{blockade_moderate_FAILURE}You have not blockaded this port, the Council bows to your infinitely wiser decision.
{blockade_moderate_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully blockaded this port; the Council applauds your decisiveness.
{blockade_distant_TITLE}Blockade Port 
{blockade_distant_PROPOSAL}It is time we apply pressure upon our foes. Sending a fleet to blockade this port for at least 1 turns will not only hurt our enemy, but it will fill our coffers.
{blockade_distant_EXPIRY_SETTLEMENT_TAKEN}This port has been taken; you are no longer expected to blockade it.
{blockade_distant_EXPIRY_ALLIED}This faction has become an ally; you are no longer required to blockade this port.
{blockade_distant_EXPIRY_BLOCKADED}It appears this port is already blockaded; you are no longer required to blockade it.
{blockade_distant_FAILURE}You have not blockaded this port, the Council bows to your infinitely wiser decision.
{blockade_distant_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully blockaded this port; the Council applauds your decisiveness.
{assassinate_captain_TITLE}Assassination Mission
{assassinate_captain_PROPOSAL}This miscreant's demise would please a great many people, not to mention make smoother our path to success. The Council suggests you send an assassin to hasten this man's journey into the next world. 
{assassinate_captain_EXPIRY_DEATH}Your target has died; you are no longer required to assassinate him.
{assassinate_captain_EXPIRY_ALLIED}This man has become our ally; it is no longer necessary to remove him.
{assassinate_captain_EXPIRY_HIDING}Your target has gone into hiding; you are no longer required to assassinate him.
{assassinate_captain_FAILURE}You have failed to assassinate this individual; the Council assumes this must be part of your great plan.
{assassinate_captain_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully assassinated this individual; the Council is impressed by your ruthlessness.
{steal_general_TITLE}A Proposal for the Princess's Hand
{steal_general_PROPOSAL}Lord %S has been beguiled by the lovely Princess %S. He is willing to pay a handsome dowry for her hand in marriage. The Council recommends you arrange this marriage as soon as possible.
{steal_general_EXPIRY_GENERAL_DEATH}Alas this marriage can never be, the general has died, and nearly left our Princess a widow.
{steal_general_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_DEATH}Alas, the poor Princess has died; we must call the marriage off.
{steal_general_EXPIRY_TARGET_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, and this lord is twice such, he has married another. The marriage to our Princess is off.
{steal_general_FAILURE_PRINCESS_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, it seems our Princess has married another, the original marriage is off.
{steal_general_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_RETIRED}Our Princess is now too old to marry; her time would be better spent on more solitary and contemplative pursuits. The marriage is off.
{steal_general_FAILURE}You have not arranged the marriage this Council recommended. The Council bows to your greater judgement in these matters.
{steal_general_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully arranged the marriage we recommended. This union is sure to bear fruit in time.
{join_crusade_TITLE}Join the Crusade
{join_crusade_LEADER_TITLE}Your Leader must join the Crusade.
{join_crusade_HEIR_TITLE}Your Heir must join the Crusade.
{join_crusade_PROPOSAL}The Pope has called a holy Crusade, and the Pope has sent the call to arms to all devoted Catholic factions. You must create a Crusading army within the time limit to take part.
{join_crusade_CHARACTER_PROPOSAL}The Pope has requested that %S demonstrate his faith and personally join the Crusade.
{join_crusade_SUCCESS}You have pleased the Pope and proven your faith by successfully joining the Crusade. 
{join_crusade_EXPIRED_FINISHED}The Crusade has ended; you can no longer join. 
{join_crusade_EXPIRED_DEATH}Your General has died. As a result, you can no longer join the Crusade.
{join_crusade_EXPIRED_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated. You have no place amongst the worthy; you can no longer join the Crusade.
{join_crusade_FAILURE}You have disappointed the Pope by not meeting your obligations to Christendom and failing to join the Crusade.
{return_papal_settlement_SUCCESS}You have greatly pleased His Holiness by successfully returning Rome to The Papal States.
{return_papal_settlement_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to return Rome to The Papal States.
{return_papal_settlement_TITLE}Return Rome to the Papal States.
{return_papal_settlement_PROPOSAL}The Pope has requested that you return Rome to The Papal States. His Holiness will be greatly in your debt if you can see fit to return his home city.
{cease_hostilities_TITLE}Cease Hostilities
{cease_hostilities_PROPOSAL}His Holiness demands that you stop shedding the blood of your fellow Christians. Cease hostilities against this faction immediately and do not carry out hostile acts for the duration of this mission.
{cease_hostilities_EXPIRY_DEATH}His Holiness is no longer concerned about the fate of this faction as it has been eliminated.
{cease_hostilities_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless and ignoble faction has been excommunicated, the Papacy no longer expects such as you to listen to the request of His Holiness.
{cease_hostilities_EXPIRY_TARGET_EXCOMMUNICATED}As this faction has been excommunicated, it matters little how much of their faithless blood you spill. You are no longer charged with ceasing hostilities with this faction.
{cease_hostilities_FAILURE}You have greatly saddened His Holiness by failing to cease hostilities with your fellow Christians, and continuing to shed the blood of your brother.
{cease_hostilities_SUCCESS}You have greatly pleased His Holiness by refraining from hostile actions against your fellow Christians. He only hopes this newfound peace will last.
{assassinate_cardinal_TITLE}Assassinate Cardinal 
{assassinate_cardinal_PROPOSAL}This Cardinal's profanity and disrespect has deeply distressed His Holiness. The Pope assures you that God himself will smile upon you if you can deal with this delicate matter (kill him!).
{assassinate_cardinal_EXPIRY_DEATH}As this Cardinal has died, His Holiness has no need for you to 'deal' with him.
{assassinate_cardinal_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}You have been excommunicated, His Holiness no longer trusts you with this important duty.
{assassinate_cardinal_EXPIRY_HIDING}This Cardinal cannot be found, His Holiness has no need for you to 'deal' with him.
{assassinate_cardinal_FAILURE}His Holiness is disquieted by your failure to 'deal' with this Cardinal.
{assassinate_cardinal_SUCCESS}You have done the Papacy a great favour, and much pleased His Holiness by successfully assassinating this Cardinal.
{assassinate_witch_heretic_TITLE}Assassinate the heretic
{assassinate_witch_heretic_PROPOSAL}This blasphemer is a stain on God's Earth and the Pope wishes you to cleanse it. Assassinate this person immediately!
{assassinate_witch_heretic_EXPIRY_DEATH}His Holiness has no need for you to assassinate this person, as they have perished.
{assassinate_witch_heretic_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated; His Holiness does not trust the likes of you to uphold the Word of God. You are no longer charged with the assassination of this person.
{assassinate_witch_heretic_EXPIRY_HIDING}His Holiness has no need for you to assassinate this person, as they cannot be found.
{assassinate_witch_heretic_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to assassinate this blasphemer as asked.
{assassinate_witch_heretic_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully assassinating this blasphemer, and thus making the world more pleasing to His eye.
{papal_blockade_port_TITLE}Blockade Port
{papal_blockade_port_PROPOSAL}The Pope only wishes that this prodigal son be returned to the fold. Perhaps cutting his income will make him see the light. Use your fleet to blockade this port for at least 3 turns.
{papal_blockade_port_EXPIRY_SETTLEMENT_TAKEN}This settlement has been taken, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{papal_blockade_port_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated. You are no longer trusted to blockade this port.
{papal_blockade_port_EXPIRY_RECOMMUNICATED}As this faction has returned to the fold and been reconciled, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{papal_blockade_port_EXPIRY_BLOCKADED}This port is already blockaded, you are no longer charged to blockade this port.
{papal_blockade_port_FAILURE}You have let down the Pope and the Almighty by unsuccessfully blockading this port.
{papal_blockade_port_SUCCESS}You have pleased the Pope and the Lord by successfully blockading this port.
{break_alliance_TITLE}Break Alliance
{break_alliance_PROPOSAL}In uncertain times like these, it is important to know who one's true allies are. The Pope demands you break your alliance with this profane and heretical faction to prove your loyalty.
{break_alliance_EXPIRY_DEATH}As this faction has perished, you are no longer required to break your alliance with them.
{break_alliance_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated. You are no longer required to break your alliance with this faction.
{break_alliance_EXPIRY_RECOMMUNICATED}As this faction has returned to the fold and been reconciled, you are no longer required to break your alliance with them.
{break_alliance_FAILURE}His Holiness can only wonder what went wrong; you have disappointed the Pope by failing to break your alliance with this faction. 
{break_alliance_SUCCESS}You have pleased the Pope and proven your loyalty by successfully breaking your alliance with this faction.
{papal_build_church_TITLE}Build a Church
{papal_build_church_PROPOSAL}It has come to His Holiness's attention that this settlement is bereft of a proper place of worship. The Pope wishes you to build a church in this settlement.
{papal_build_church_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this settlement, you are no longer charged with building a church there.
{papal_build_church_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your faithless faction has been excommunicated; the Pope cares naught what you build in this settlement.
{papal_build_church_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to build a church in this settlement, and thus hampering the proper worship of the Lord in this settlement.
{papal_build_church_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully building a church in this settlement, and thus propagating the proper worship of the Lord in this settlement.
{convert_TITLE}Spread the Word of the Lord
{convert_PROPOSAL}The Pope sees that the unbelievers in this settlement are clouding the judgement of the righteous. Send a priest to convert at least %d %% of the population to Catholicism.
{convert_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your ungodly faction has been excommunicated. One cannot expect a nest of vipers to bring forward the lambs. You are no longer charged with converting the people to the 'one true faith. 
{convert_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to convert sufficient people in this settlement.
{convert_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully spreading the word and bringing more lambs to His flock in this settlement.
{gift_from_pope_TITLE}A Gift from the Pope
{gift_from_pope_PROPOSAL}The Pope has noticed your dedication to the Faith and the Holy Mother Church and is pleased to grant you this gift.
{give_cash_TITLE}Give a "donation" to the Pope
{give_cash_PROPOSAL}The Lord favours he who is generous. Make a "donation" of at least %d florins to the Papal States. 
{give_cash_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness with your selfishness, by failing to "donate" sufficient florins to the Papal States.
{give_cash_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness with your generous "donation" to the Papal States. Blessed is he who gives.
{give_ancillary_TITLE}Give Relic to the Pope
{give_ancillary_PROPOSAL}The Pope has heard of your retrieval of this wondrous holy relic and sends his congratulations. You must hand over this relic to the Pope so that it may reside with his Holiness as is proper.
{give_ancillary_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by coveting this relic and thus failing to hand it over to His Holiness.
{give_ancillary_SUCCESS}The Pope sends you his gratitude for the rightful return of this holy relic to the Catholic Church.
{recruit_priest_TITLE}Recruit a Priest
{recruit_priest_PROPOSAL}The dwindling number of Catholics in this settlement reflects poorly on the Catholic Church. Recruit a priest in this settlement to convert more people.
{recruit_priest_EXPIRY_LOST}You have lost this settlement, you are no longer charged with recruiting a priest.
{recruit_priest_EXPIRY_EXCOMMUNICATED}Your worthless faction has been excommunicated, a priest from such a flock would be at best worthless. You are no longer charged with recruiting a priest.
{recruit_priest_FAILURE}You have disappointed His Holiness by failing to recruit a priest, and thus hampering His Holy work.
{recruit_priest_SUCCESS}You have pleased His Holiness by successfully recruiting a priest, and thus creating yet another vessel for His word.
{assassinate_general_TITLE}Assassination Mission
{assassinate_general_PROPOSAL}This miscreant's demise would please a great many people, not to mention make smoother our path to success. The Council suggests you send an assassin to hasten this man's journey into the next world. 
{assassinate_general_EXPIRY_DEATH}Your target has died; you are no longer required to assassinate him.
{assassinate_general_EXPIRY_ALLIED}This man has become our ally; it is no longer necessary to remove him.
{assassinate_general_EXPIRY_HIDING}Your target has gone into hiding; you are no longer required to assassinate him.
{assassinate_general_FAILURE}You have failed to assassinate this individual; the Council assumes this must be part of your great plan.
{assassinate_general_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully assassinated this individual; the Council is impressed by your ruthlessness.
{council_blockade_port_TITLE}Blockade Port 
{council_blockade_port_PROPOSAL}It is time we apply pressure upon our foes. Sending a fleet to blockade this port for at least 3 turns will not only hurt our enemy, but it will fill our coffers.
{council_blockade_port_EXPIRY_SETTLEMENT_TAKEN}This port has been taken; you are no longer expected to blockade it.
{council_blockade_port_EXPIRY_ALLIED}This faction has become an ally; you are no longer required to blockade this port.
{council_blockade_port_EXPIRY_BLOCKADED}It appears this port is already blockaded; you are no longer required to blockade it.
{council_blockade_port_FAILURE}You have not blockaded this port, the Council bows to your infinitely wiser decision.
{council_blockade_port_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully blockaded this port; the Council applauds your decisiveness.
{council_take_rebel_settlement_TITLE}Take Rebel Settlement
{council_take_rebel_settlement_PROPOSAL}Our great nation appears weak to tolerate such insolence from these rebels. The Council recommends you capture this rebel settlement and assert your authority.
{council_take_rebel_settlement_EXPIRY_LOST}Another has taken this Rebel settlement. You are no longer required to take it.
{council_take_rebel_settlement_FAILURE}It appears you have decided against this Council's advice by not taking this Rebel settlement, the Council can only assume this is yet another sudden turn in your labyrinth-like plan.
{council_take_rebel_settlement_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully taken this Rebel settlement and displayed our strength to all.
{council_take_settlement_TITLE}Take Settlement
{council_take_settlement_PROPOSAL}It is time to further our great empire by extending our borders. The Council suggests you take this settlement for the glory of the nation.
{council_take_settlement_EXPIRY_LOST}Another has taken this settlement.
{council_take_settlement_EXPIRY_ALLIED}This faction has become an ally; you are no longer required to take it.
{council_take_settlement_FAILURE}You have failed to take this settlement; perhaps you felt it was not the right time to expand our borders?
{council_take_settlement_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully taken this settlement, and extended our Empire.
{gift_from_council_TITLE}A Gift from the Council
{gift_from_council_PROPOSAL}The Council are greatly impressed by your leadership and would like you to accept this humble offering as a token of past and future endeavours.
{council_marry_princess_TITLE}A Proposal for the Princess's Hand
{council_marry_princess_PROPOSAL}Lord %S has been beguiled by the lovely Princess %S. He is willing to pay a handsome dowry for her hand in marriage. The Council recommends you arrange this marriage as soon as possible.
{council_marry_princess_EXPIRY_GENERAL_DEATH}Alas this marriage can never be, the general has died, and nearly left our Princess a widow.
{council_marry_princess_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_DEATH}Alas, the poor Princess has died; we must call the marriage off.
{council_marry_princess_EXPIRY_TARGET_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, and this lord is twice such, he has married another. The marriage to our Princess is off.
{council_marry_princess_FAILURE_PRINCESS_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, it seems our Princess has married another, the original marriage is off.
{council_marry_princess_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_RETIRED}Our Princess is now too old to marry; her time would be better spent on more solitary and contemplative pursuits. The marriage is off.
{council_marry_princess_FAILURE}You have not arranged the marriage this Council recommended. The Council bows to your greater judgement in these matters.
{council_marry_princess_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully arranged the marriage we recommended. This union is sure to bear fruit in time.
{annex_settlement_TITLE}Annex Settlement
{annex_settlement_PROPOSAL}By rights, this settlement should be under our authority. It is a mockery for it to be held by our rivals. The Council suggests you send a diplomat and attempt to have them to hand it over. You may be able to offer them a settlement that is less valuable to us in exchange.
{annex_settlement_EXPIRY_DEATH}The faction you were to treaty with has been vanquished. There is no longer a need for you to send a diplomat to them. 
{annex_settlement_EXPIRY_LOST}Another faction has taken this settlement. There is no longer a need for you to send a diplomat to this faction.
{annex_settlement_FAILURE}You have failed to convince our rivals to hand over this settlement; the Council is greatly disappointed at this turn of events.
{annex_settlement_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully convinced this faction to hand over land that is rightfully ours; the Council is much impressed by your obvious authority.
{send_emissary_TITLE}Send Emissary
{send_emissary_PROPOSAL}There are foreigners almost at our very gates and we know very little of them. The Council suggests you send an emissary to this faction and initiate diplomatic relations.
{send_emissary_EXPIRY_DEATH}The faction you were to meet with has been vanquished. There is no longer a need for you to send a diplomat to them.
{send_emissary_FAILURE}You have failed to establish diplomatic relations with these people, the Council hopes this is for the best.
{send_emissary_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully established diplomatic relations with these people; the Council admires the ease with which you handle diplomacy.
{reinforce_region_TITLE}Reinforce Region
{reinforce_region_PROPOSAL}This region is the frontier to our enemies, but is undermanned and vulnerable to attack. The Council suggests you increase our forces here by at least 4 units.
{reinforce_region_EXPIRY_LOST}It is too late, the settlement is lost! It can no longer be reinforced by our forces.
{reinforce_region_FAILURE}You have failed to reinforce this region and left it vulnerable to attack, the Council hopes this is all part of some master strategy.
{reinforce_region_SUCCESS}Well done, you have successfully reinforced this region against attacks from our foes, the Council is comforted by your wisdom.
{guild_take_settlement_TITLE}Take Settlement
{guild_take_settlement_PROPOSAL}The Guild's interests would be better looked after if this settlement were to become part of your empire. The Guild requests that you take this settlement.
{guild_take_settlement_EXPIRY_LOST}Another has taken this settlement, the Guild no longer requires you to take it.
{guild_take_settlement_EXPIRY_ALLIED}An alliance has been forged with this settlement, the Guild no longer requires you to take it.
{guild_take_settlement_FAILURE}You have failed to take this settlement; the Guild is disappointed with this lack of progress.
{guild_take_settlement_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully taken this settlement; the Guild owes you its thanks.
{guild_recruit_agent_TITLE}Train Assassin
{guild_recruit_agent_PROPOSAL}Sometimes a single drop of poison or one knife in the dark can achieve what an entire army cannot. The Guild requests that you train an assassin in this settlement.
{guild_recruit_agent_EXPIRY_LOST}As you have lost this settlement, the Guild no longer expects you to train an assassin there.
{guild_recruit_agent_FAILURE}You have failed to train an assassin; the Guild is disappointed with this result.
{guild_recruit_agent_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully trained an assassin, the Guild is very pleased.
{guild_acquisition_TITLE}Mercantile Acquisition
{guild_acquisition_PROPOSAL}There is lucrative trade to be had here, but first we must deal with the opposition. The Guild recommends you send your merchant to make an acquisition of this merchants' trade. 
{guild_acquisition_EXPIRY_DEATH}It appears this merchant has perished; we no longer need to remove him.
{guild_acquisition_EXPIRY_HIDING}It appears this merchant has gone into hiding; we no longer need to remove him. 
{guild_acquisition_FAILURE}You have failed to complete the desired acquisition; the Guild is disappointed with this outcome. 
{guild_acquisition_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully made the acquisition; the Guild owes you its thanks.
{guild_trade_agreement_TITLE}Obtain Trade Agreement
{guild_trade_agreement_PROPOSAL}We are losing lucrative trade opportunities, as we currently have no trade Agreement with this faction. The Guild would like you to obtain a trade agreement with these people.
{guild_trade_agreement_EXPIRY_DEATH}This faction has been vanquished; a trade agreement with them is no longer possible.
{guild_trade_agreement_EXPIRY_WAR}These fools have chosen war with us rather than peaceful trade. So be it, a trade agreement with them is no longer possible. 
{guild_trade_agreement_FAILURE}You have not obtained a trade agreement with this faction; the Guild is disappointed with this outcome.
{guild_trade_agreement_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully obtained a Trade Agreement with this faction; the Guild owes you its thanks.
{guild_build_TITLE}A Gift from the Mason's Guild
{guild_build_PROPOSAL}In recognition of your past aid and support to the Mason's Guild, the masons will build a place of worship in your honour, so that the faithful may gather.
{regicide_TITLE}Regicide
{regicide_PROPOSAL}My father is naught but a simpering fool. If left to rule he will bring only ruin to what should be my empire. Kill him so that I may lead my empire to greatness, and our empires will rule the world side by side as brothers. I am willing to generously 'recompense' you for your troubles.
{regicide_EXPIRY_DEATH}My 'noble' father has perished; you are no longer required to 'intervene'.
{regicide_EXPIRY_SOURCE_DEATH}The heir to this man's throne has passed away and you are no longer required to carry out his dark deeds. Of course, you wouldn't want your hard work to go to waste, and there's no harm in eliminating another rival.
{regicide_EXPIRY_HIDING}My father has gone to ground like the mole he is, you are no longer required to 'intervene'. 
{regicide_FAILURE}You have failed to deal with my wretched father as I requested, I will not forget this.
{regicide_SUCCESS}You have my endless gratitude; you have done both my people and myself a great favour. Your deed may go unsung but it will not go unrewarded, nor forgotten.
{crusade_active_TITLE}A Holy Crusade
{crusade_active_PROPOSAL}The Pope has called for a holy Crusade to this settlement. It is time for righteous steel and arms strengthened by faith to free this part of God's land from his enemies.
{crusade_active_TARGET_PROPOSAL}It is a nightmarish day for your people that inhabit this settlement, for the Pope has called a holy Crusade against it! The seemingly endless armies of Christendom will soon be marching to lay siege to the walls... Make peace with the Pope, or make ready to defend it!
{jihad_active_TITLE}A Jihad
{jihad_active_PROPOSAL}A Jihad is moving on this settlement to clean away the infidels. It is time to dispense rightful anger upon these snakes in men's clothing.
{jihad_active_TARGET_PROPOSAL}A great Imam has called for the warriors of Islam to take up holy Jihad against your people and descend upon this settlement! The willingness of the Muslim soldiers' to die for such a cause make this one of the most terrifying perils the people of this place will ever face... Ensure they are prepared.
